有多少种颜色？这听起来像一个非常简单的问题但是
How many colors are there? It sounds like a very simple question but
答案远非简单。人们普遍认为彩虹中有七种颜色。
the answer is far from simple. It’s commonly agreed that there are seven colors in a rainbow.
他们是红，橙，黄，绿，蓝，靛，紫。如果你问绘儿乐
They are red, orange, yellow, green, blue, indigo and violet. If you ask the Crayola
公司，制作蜡笔的人，他们有120种不同颜色的蜡笔
Company, the people who make crayons, they’ve got 120 different colored crayons in their
范围。描述网页的HTML语言有121种唯一命名的颜色
range. The HTML language, which describes web pages, has got 121 uniquely named colors
我们可以使用。许多基于Unix的操作系统，例如非常流行的Linux
that we can use. Many Unix-based operating systems, for instance, the very popular Linux
操作系统，有一个名为X11的窗口系统，并附带X11发行版
operating system, have a windowing system called X11, and X11 distributions come with
一个名为RGB.text的文件，它列出了一大堆不同颜色，最后一次
a file called RGB.text, which lists a whole bunch of different colors, and the last time
我查看了这个包含881种不同颜色的文件。
I looked at this file it contained 881 different colors.
如果你看一下英语中所有单词的集合，他们称之为
If you look at a collection of all the words in the English language, what they call the
英语语料库，我们用大约4000个不同的单词来描述颜色。
English Corpus, there are around 4000 different words that we use to describe colors.
另一个有一个复杂答案的简单问题是“一种颜色在哪里结束”
Another simple question that’s got a complex answer is ‘where does one color end and
另一种颜色开始？'所以在这里我们可以看到一个包含一系列颜色的图形
another color start?’. So over here we can see a figure which contains a range of colors
来自红色，黄色，绿色，蓝色等。在最近的一次演习中，他们进行了调查
from reds, yellows, greens, blues, and so on. And in a recent exercise they surveyed
大量的网络用户，150万网络用户，并要求他们之间划分界限
a large number of web users, 1.5 million web users, and asked them to draw boundaries between
不同的颜色，并命名他们。这是150万网络的共识
the different colors, and to name them. And this is a consensus across 1.5 million web
用户。它显示了人们倾向于认为绿色和他们认为是蓝色的东西
users. It shows what people tend to agree as being green and what they think is blue
他们认为是青色的等等。这很困难，因为我们试图描绘
and what they think is teal and so on. This is difficult because we’re trying to delineate
颜色和颜色的区域是连续的，我们试图强制执行任意的
regions in color, and color is a continuum, and we’re trying to enforce sort of arbitrary
这种其他连续的颜色概念的界限。
boundaries across this otherwise continuous notion of color.
我们解释颜色的方式也取决于我们的文化背景。在亚洲，橙色是
The way we interpret color also depends on our cultural background. In Asia, orange is
一种非常非常积极的颜色，但在美国，澳大利亚和欧洲部分地区，橙色
a very, very positive color, but in the United States, Australia and parts of Europe, orange
被认为是危险或危险的颜色。例如，一些非洲语言，
is considered to be a color of danger or of hazard. Some African languages, for example,
没有任何区分红色和橙色的词。然而，
do not have any words which distinguish the color red from the color orange. However,
所有语言都有单词来描述黑白，如果语言已经有了
all of the languages have got words to describe black and white, and if the language has got
比这两种更多的颜色，它们将描述的下一个最可能的颜色
more colors than just those two, the next most likely color that they are going to describe
是红色，接下来很可能是黄色或绿色。蓝色经常是第六个命名
is red, and next most likely is either yellow or green. Blue is frequently the sixth named
许多语言的颜色，所以蓝色真的不如红色和绿色，黑色和
color in many languages, so blue really is not as important as red and green, black and
白色。布朗来晚了，然后是我们有名字的所有其他颜色。
white. Brown comes later and then all of the other colors that we’ve got names for.
这个相当复杂的图表显示了文化之间的关系，表示为
This rather complex graph shows a relationship between the culture, which is indicated by
这里的字母和由径向颜色条表示的情感编号
the letters here, and the emotion, which is indicated by the radial color bars, numbered
从1到284.我们可以看到用于表示的非常不同的颜色
from 1 through 284. What we can see is the very different colors that are used to represent
跨文化的不同情感或感受。如果我们看一下颜色术语的出现
different emotions or feelings across cultures. If we look at the occurrence of color terms
例如，英语语料库中包含大量英语单词
in a big collection of English words, for instance, the Bank of English Corpus contains
很多来自美国，英国和澳大利亚的文献，
a lot of literature from the United States, United Kingdom, and Australia for example,
然后我们可以看一下这些颜色词出现的直方图。我们看到黑色
then we could look at a histogram of the occurrence of those color words. And we see that black
是迄今为止最常出现的词，其次是白色，其次是红色，绿色
is by far the most frequently occurring word, followed by white, followed by red, green
蓝色等等，而最少出现的单词就像深蓝色和黄绿色。
blue and so on, whereas the least occurring words are those like ultramarine and chartreuse.
最常见的颜色词也是最古老的。所以1200年前并没有那么多
The most common color words are also the oldest. So 1200 years ago there weren’t that many
不同颜色的单词，但随着时间的推移，我们引入了越来越多的颜色词
different color words but as time has passed we’ve introduced more and more color words
进入我们的词汇。800年左右有一个很大的转折点，我们改变了
into our vocabulary. There’s a big transition point around the year 800, where we changed
从关注亮度，谈论白色，黑色，灰色等，我们开始的地方
from a focus just on brightness, talking about white, black, grey and so on, where we started
对谈论色调，实际的颜色，而不仅仅是
to get more interested in talking about the hue, the actual color, rather than just the
亮度。也许这也是一种技术转变，也许是染料和染料
brightness. Perhaps this was a technological transition as well, perhaps when dyes and
颜料变得更加普遍。Pantone公司的整个生计都是
pigments became much more common. The Pantone company’s whole livelihood is
基于颜色。它们对颜色进行编目，它们使用唯一数字描述所有颜色
based on color. They catalogue colors, they describe all of the colors using unique numeric
代码，它们每年都会推广一年的颜色。所以2013年的颜色
codes, and they promote every year a color of the year. So the color of the year in 2013
这是绿色的。底线是颜色对人类来说真的非常重要。
is this green. The bottom line is that color is really, really important to humans.